I get a ribbing from my friends because
[music] I say I'm not a developer. If
you were already using a web tool like
Claude or ChattyPT, I think one of the
ones I would look at is typing mind. If
I go back to the chat and I say write
like Popey, this has a prompt in it that
says write a blog post the way Allan
would write. You're not locked to one of
the providers. I could start the chat
and say actually I want to do this with
Gemini or I want to do this with Chat
GPT. People are trying to learn the best
practices for themselves probably way
too much in isolation.
>> Sometimes you configure an MCP in your
agent and then it goes away and so it
can be a bit dangerous having [music]
this tool hanging around in your
MCP.json file that you think [music] it
could be that that's actually a
liability.
>> What would you say is one of the next
big things that we should be thinking?
>> I think I'd say
[music]
Before we jump into this episode, I
wanted to let you know that this podcast
is for developers building with AI at
the core. So whether that's exploring
the latest tools, the workflows, or the
best practices, this podcast's for you.
A really quick ask, 90% of people who
are listening to this haven't yet
subscribed. So if this content has
helped you build smarter, hit that
subscribe button and maybe a like. All
right, back to the episode. Hello and
welcome to another episode of the AI
Native Dev. And last week we had a
little bit of a a 101 with Max on AI
agents. And today we're going to
continue that practical theme and
continue talking about various agents,
how you can use agents, but also how we
can extend the capabilities of agents
through MCP servers. and not just talk
about them, but we're actually going to
see and have a play with uh some of Alan
Pope's uh favorite MCP servers and and
servers that he's played with in the
past and talk about the tools uh that
provide the capabilities that those MCP
servers uh offer. So, yeah, I mentioned
Alan, Mr. Alan Pope. Alan, very very
welcome to the AI Native Dev podcast.
How are you?
>> Thanks very much. Yeah, it's great to be
here. I've been watching for a while and
now I get to be on it, which is lovely.
>> Long time long time listener, first-
time caller, right? Yes, exactly.
[laughter]
>> So, Alan, tell us a little bit about who
Allan was before we met maybe and then
and then today
>> I think I I get a ribbing from my
friends because uh I say I'm not a
developer. Uh I didn't do I didn't study
software engineering. I've been a Devril
and community manager for a long time
and I can write some code. But I found
in the last few years, all of the
different developments with LLMs have
accelerated me from the ideas that I
have uh turning them into actual usable
pieces of software and actually
sometimes even publishing them on the
internet for people to you know
critique, review and use and contribute
to. And so I think um it's been a real
accelerant just for me personally using
uh LLMs because I would often find it
difficult to get started, not know what
tools to use, not know what frameworks
to use, uh not understand everything
that I was doing and this has just made
life a little bit happier for me cuz I
can finish things.
>> Yeah. Amazing. And and when we when we
first met, we we grabbed a coffee in a
in a in a local Starbucks and we just
kind of like geeked out on all things
specifications and and I guess what what
was the what was the drive that kind of
made you lean more into specifications?
What was the problem that made you
think, do you know what, we need to we
need to grow this out into a larger spec
versus versus more of a prompt style
approach?
>> Yeah. So I think I'm already my mind was
already in the space of I want to
describe what I want because I felt like
if I can [clears throat] describe what I
want uh at some point I will have the
time and capabilities to turn that into
code right but I what I need to do first
is write it all up in English in a way
that I and other people can understand.
So, I would often run these I wouldn't
call them specs. They were like design
documents and I'd run them past uh
[clears throat] other friends who were
software developers and sometimes I'd
end up nerd sniping them into doing it
for me. And sometimes I'd just get their
critique, their review, and they'd say,
"No, that will never work." Or, "Yes,
that's a good idea. Someone should do
that." And it would go filed away in the
big list of projects that Alan would
like to finish one day. Uh and then when
the whole specbas based development
started uh like gaining traction, I felt
like this was my time because there are
these uh documents that I've written
that I fully understand. [clears throat]
But communicating that and conveying
that into you know a uh a software
developer's head is hard. Um, but
[clears throat] conveying that to an LLM
that understands what I want
as far as they can understand and can
turn that into how to make that a thing
that I can run and with a spec that is
more technical and not so much a design
document, but a technical specification
of okay, we're going to use Python,
we're going to use UV to do
dependencies, we're going to have a a
particular database for the back end,
and this is what the API should look
like. That's the bit that I was missing.
And with the specs I can identify best
practices and also uh [clears throat]
identify how I implement those best
practices. And so it's kind of that's
the bit that's missing. And it there was
quite a learning exercise in discovering
all of the the ways in which you use
these tools and agents and and specs.
And I think I'm quite keen on sharing
what I do because I feel like there's a
gap and people don't often know how to
get from chatting to an LLM to creating
a finished project. And that's that's
sometimes because they just don't know
what they don't know. And so I'm I'm
very keen on sharing that kind of
information.
>> Interesting. And a lot of what you were
saying is really guidance. It's not
necessarily just what the thing you want
to build is. It's a lot of guidance in
terms of how you want the agent to go
about building that as well. The
It was funny actually. We we chatted in
the office the other day and uh you you
were we were talking about tools and
tool usage and and one of the one of the
things that we talked about is how you
go about finding and identifying those
tools. And we're going to talk about a
ton of tools here today. We're going to
talk about we're going to talk about
claw gemini CLI uh uh typing mind uh
we're going to maybe talk a little bit
about various MCP servers that do things
like sequential thinking and and uh fire
crawl and and maybe Tesla YouTube uh
access and all those types of things.
But Alan, how do you kind of identify,
you know, where you want to uh grab
these tools from? what what what kind of
what's the thing that makes motivates
you to try them out and and and learn
about them?
>> So, initially it was I just needed the
the thing to get going and so there
there are a few uh tools that I've used
that got me got me started and now I
have an understanding of the landscape.
I'm trying to find new things that can
make me go faster or replace manual
processes. So, for example, one of the
ones you mentioned is a YouTube
transcription downloader. So, go and get
the transcription of a video because
there's a lot of words in there and you
could use those words in the creation of
other content like social posts and blog
posts and that kind of stuff. And as
part of Devril, that's something I would
do. Now, I'd already written a
[clears throat] little shell script that
uses YTDLP, a popular like YouTube
downloader tool, but [clears throat]
that was manual. I had to like run YTDLP
and the URL. Whereas what I was thinking
would be better is if there was an MCP
that could do that for me while I'm in
the flow of creating a blog post and I'm
in the zone and I don't have to jump out
to use some terribly written shell
script from me or uh use some third
party tool. I can have it all
integrated. And so having a conversation
with an LLM where it can branch off and
go, okay, I'll now I'll go and get those
transcriptions and then now I'll do the
summary and then let's figure out what
keywords people are looking for and do
all those things but outsource them to
the tools that can do those things best.
That's that's the the part that I find
interesting. The the tricky part is
where do you discover these things? And
sometimes it's it's simply word of
mouth. I sit having coffee with a friend
and they tell me the things they've
discovered over the weekend and that's
not scalable. It's great for me and
great for him but it's not scalable and
I think we do need better ways to share
uh the tools and settings even like
>> [snorts]
>> uh the the little configuration settings
for each of your agents those kind of
things and then you sit there and read
through all of the documentation for
everything you know and ain't nobody got
time for that. So, I'd way rather have
recommendations from other people and
rated um tools and MCP servers that that
I can
>> make a qualitative decision about
whether I'm going to use that or not.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Cool. Let's talk about
agents a little bit now and jump into uh
I guess which agents you had potentially
talked about word of mouth and and and
recommending these agents. For someone
who's never really used, let's say, a
coding agent before, we have to first, I
guess, recognize there are different
styles of agents, a an agent is just
something that can go away and do
something very autonomously. Uh perform
various tasks. Uh maybe maybe even call
out to sub agents and other agents to
perform those tasks. Uh it doesn't
necessarily say anything about the UI as
to how you interact with that. very
often chat based uh sometimes in a UI
that is web oriented sometimes others.
Where where would how would you
recommend to people to try and use an AI
agent first? Is it up to them? Is it the
best tool on the market? Where would you
go? You know, this is one of those
tricky things where it's changing all
the time and I know a lot of people uh
just use chat GPT and they just chat to
it in a web page or in the app and
they'll ask it to create something and
it will do that. And certainly over time
all of the agents that are available,
the popular ones have improved
dramatically. They It used to be you'd
get into an angry argument with an agent
trying to get them to do what you want
and get them to understand what you
want. Um and eventually you'd fill up
their context window and um it would
forget what you originally asked them
for. And things have got a lot better
now where many of the web- based agents
have code editors built in and that some
of them have got a place where you can
run and test the code directly in the
web page. And so [snorts] my experience
from early use of chat GPT to write code
or early use of uh claude in a web page
to use code is probably very different
now um because people could just open a
web page and they've got a code editor
right there. Um so I think my experience
might be colored by the the fact that
I've been doing this for a while. And by
a while I mean like a year or more like
that's still not very long. Um, so I
think if you were already using uh
[clears throat] a web tool like Claude
uh or chatpt I think one of the ones I
would look at is uh typing mind. Now,
type in mind is interesting because it's
same web type UI, but it's super
configurable in that you can connect it
to external tools to do things like
download the YouTube um uh thumbnails or
the uh transcription or get it to go and
search online for more information or
connect directly to GitHub or whatever
the things you need to do as part of
your development to do research and and
software development. But the nice thing
is it has this web UI, but it is super
configurable. And so, um, if you look at
the example I've got here, you can
create these things called agents. Now,
these are, uh, you know, when you think
of the term agent, it's a bit of an
overloaded term. And in here, it means
like a personality of an agent. So, it's
it's prepared with a a prompt, and it
may have access to some knowledge that
you've uploaded. So, for example, here's
a very simple example that I've used.
this one here called write like popy now
all I've done is in typing mind I've
updated a knowledge base which over here
on the left hand side and in the
knowledge base you can upload documents
that uh your agents in typing mind will
have access to and so down here I've got
one called popy blogs and I've had a
blog since about 1997 or something and I
grabbed all the source for all of the
articles that I've ever written and put
them in here so that I can have typing
mind help me write an article that
sounds like I wrote it. Now I realize
that sounds like I'm just, you know, not
ever going to write any any blogs again
because I'm just going to leave it up to
Typing Mind to do it, but I did it as a
test. I haven't actually used it an
awful lot. I've used it a couple of
times, but it's quite remarkable that
once it knows your style of writing and
your tone of voice and the way that you
write, uh it's very um
uh able to create new content that looks
like you wrote it. It's it's quite
surprising. I can I can give you a
little demo. If I uh go back to the chat
and I say write like Popey, this has a
prompt in it that says write a blog
post, you know, the way Allan would
write. And down here you can give it
access to those MCP servers that we'll
talk about a little bit more a bit
later. [snorts] But you can also give it
access to um the knowledge
[clears throat] base. And if I say, you
know, um, right, uh, oh, right, I can't
type, write, uh, blog about new
developments,
MCP servers
in the command line.
So you the other thing you'll notice
while I'm while it's chugging away,
you'll see down here it says cla. Um,
one of the nice thing about uh, typing
mind is you're not locked to one of the
providers. I could start the chat and
say actually I want to do this with
Gemini or I want to do this with chat
GPT and you can even fork conversations
partway through and change from one
model to another. So this is quite an
advantage over just sitting in the chat
GPT web UI or the clawed web UI because
I I'm you know claudes don't give you
access to chat GPT and vice versa. And
so there's some interesting options in
here. Now, you'll notice here it's gone
and found
>> [clears throat]
>> uh a blog post that I wrote some time
ago called Command line only laptop,
which is a ThinkPad that I had a while
ago. Um, and then it like reads a few
more things, some other articles that
I've written. Um, and down here,
I mean, this is exactly the style of
content I would write. I put a TLDDR at
the top and then I'd write far too many
words. And so it it's got that style
exactly right. Um and you know
subheadings like what on earth is MCP?
That kind of stuff. That's the style of
writing that I have. So the [snorts]
thing I like about typing mind is it's
doing a lot of things all within one
user interface. It's able to connect to
different uh tools. It's able to uh have
[clears throat] knowledge uploaded to
it. Uh not just blog posts like
documentation or existing code. Um and I
can access this from anywhere. uh
because I I've signed up and I can
access this on my mobile phone and have
a conversation and actually start a
conversation and some software being
developed and then walk away and
continue somewhere else. One of the
other things that it has which is really
cool [snorts] is one of the uh MCPs, one
of the tools that it has access to is
called file system. And this is handy
because I'm on a web page, but I can
give this tool access to specific
directories on my machine and say write
the code directly on my machine. And
that gets away from what we used to do,
which is like have a conversation with
an LLM and copy and paste the code out
of the conversation. With this, it just
goes directly to that folder and will
start creating files. And when you go to
that folder, you'll see the the software
we created. And then later on, I could
use the GitHub MCP to have it actually
create a repository on GitHub and upload
the whole thing and upload the readme
and even make the readme sound like me
and in the style of my other readme. So,
it's I find this is a good um tool type
in mind, a good agent for doing a lot of
different things in one place without
you having to switch between, you know,
all kinds of different uh tools and
utilities. And if you prefer the web UI,
this is great for that. And it's amazing
because it feel it feels quite generic
in the sense of it's not necessar
specifically for coding or specifically
for writing blogs. But I guess that's
the power of MCPs uh an MCP servers to
be able to connect you with those
specific uh tasks that you might uh that
you might want the agent to branch out
and call an MCP directly for. Um I'd
love to I'd love to maybe do some
testing here, Alan. see if uh see if you
could write 10 10 different blogs or so
and uh five of which you wrote manually,
five of which uh you use this for and we
can see maybe if uh if if folks who know
your style of writing can guess which
ones are from you, which ones are from
AI? Uh do do you have to do much editing
on on these blogs? Yeah, I I will always
edit because they sometimes still do get
a little bit excitable and uh you know
use phrases that I would never use or
use
>> [clears throat and snorts]
>> um terms superlatives that I would never
use but it's surprisingly good in terms
of is it convincing. Um, I also used
this to create uh webinar abstracts um
in a past job. And the way I did that
was I looked at the potential person we
were going to talk to and I scraped
their LinkedIn of every post they've
made recently, their social media. I
then went to the open-source project
that they maintain and I scraped the
last five uh meeting notes for their
open source project that that they talk
about. And I put that all in there and I
said, "Give me a webinar synopsis that
this person could talk authoritatively
on topics that they clearly like." um
and then gave them the webinar
[clears throat and snorts] uh format,
synopsis format that we use in the
company and it came up with an abstract
that was pretty much spoton and I sent
it to uh my boss and they were like,
"Yep, that's great. That's exactly what
we're after." And I sent it to the
person I was going to be discussing this
with and they said, "Yep, I can talk
about all of that." I was like, "Well,
there we go.
>> We totally should have done that for
this podcast, Alan. [laughter]
Let let's switch.
>> Yeah, maybe. Maybe. Who knows? We'll
never know. Let's um let's talk a little
bit about uh a more specific tool now
cuz like like we said, this is this can
be used for many many things uh
including those synopsis. And I guess
you could use something like Claude Code
for similar things and it probably won't
complain. It'll do it'll do what it's
told or what it's asked for. But Claude
code is much much more of a developers
tool in the sense of if someone wanted
to to to make changes to code, create
new projects, uh claude code could be a
a great a great starting point. Um talk
us through terminal AI agents and I I
guess this really only appeared earlier
this year I suppose right? Um,
are you a fan of the first of all, what
is a terminal UI and are you a fan of
it?
>> Good lord, yes. Uh, uh, so my, uh, when
[clears throat] Cloud Code first came
out, I was, um, using VS Code and GitHub
Copilot. So a familiar graphical IDE
that everyone's seen and down the side
you have a chat with an agent co-pilot
and it you know helps you update or
create projects um directly in the in
the IDE with Claude uh it's a little
different um but it depends how you use
it like you can just uh jump into a
terminal and we could uh create a
project in AID and call it I don't know
um
[snorts]
project five. This is my fifth project
that I'm doing today, I guess. And just
launch Claude
and ask it to create something like
there's there's no IDE here. I'm not
looking at any code. I'm not um within
some other tool. I am directly talking
to Claude here. And at this point, I can
ask it, you know, create a
Uh [snorts]
right now
we're all criy that's uh API error
[clears throat]
that happens. Uh so [laughter]
luckily it recovered. Uh so I just
guessed what to do there. This is not a
prepared demo. I literally just said
create a thing in a language that I I
don't know uh to do a thing um that I
would like to achieve. Right? I I quite
like having RSS readers. Now, under the
covers, obviously, this is going to be
creating code in this folder and that
will appear at some point. It's going to
create files and I don't know, maybe I
do or don't have cargo installed or I do
or don't have all the relevant bits, but
it's going to start um munching away on
the knowledge that it has and whatever
it's found via whatever tools it has
access to and it's going to start
creating some code. Whether it works or
not, I don't know. But [snorts] I've not
had to give it an awful lot of
preparation. I literally that one line
is all I told it and I haven't done any
prep for this. That was just a you know
spur of the moment suggestion and that's
quite freeing like not having this
entire IDE in front of you but just
having a chat with a thing that may or
may not be able to create what what you
envisionage right now what I'm
envisaging is yeah a list of uh feeds
and I click on a feed and I see the the
most recent um articles and I click on
an article and it expands them. I don't
know if that's really what this is going
to create. That's what I have in my
mind. And I think that's the whole um
dare we say it vibe coding of a few
months ago was [clears throat] very much
like just blurt out one line and just
say, "Yep, let's go. Do it, do it, do
it, do it, do it." And away it goes and
creates a thing or it doesn't. And it
may work or it may not, right? I I don't
feel I want to do that. I want to create
things where I can clearly articulate
what it is I want. Like I don't think
it's enough to say create an RSS reader
in in Rust. It might be and what kind of
what kind of claude code developer are
you? Are you or what kind of aentic
developer are you? Are you the kind of
person who short prompts and then
iterates to try and say actually I would
rather this than the way you did it or
uh I want to you know tighten up these
requirements over here or do you
actually long prompt to start off with
whereby that first prompt is quite
detailed in terms of what the style of
the app is maybe what stack you want it
to be run on and a number of
capabilities which which do you
naturally fit into? I think I've evolved
from and I think what a lot of people
have done is they've evolved from that
the short prompt to the to the the
longer prompt uh simply because it can
get quite exhausting
uh when you you you have an idea of what
you want but you didn't articulate it
fully um and so the the the agent tries
the best account with the information
it's given um and so what I now tend to
do is be very clear, very specific,
almost too verbose because I I really
want to steer the agent from the start.
And what I will often do is set the
permissions. So these little prompts
that pop up that you're seeing now where
it's asking, should I have to install
this thing or should I u modify these
files in the current directory? I will
often say yes to all of those or
configure in my claude settings to allow
it to edit in that folder because I
actually want to give it a quite verbose
prompt and then I want it to go away and
leave me alone for a while so that when
I come back there's something useful for
me to see and I'm not I don't come back
to the screen and see it's waiting
asking me a silly question, right? I
want it to just put as much effort in
first and then ask me. And in fact, I've
got a setting on uh my Claude because I
quite like multitasking. I'll
[clears throat] have Claude running
maybe while I'm watching a film or maybe
while I'm making dinner for the family
and I'll have an idea and I think, "Oh,
let's see if Claude can do this." And
I'll type as much as I possibly can and
I have a clause setting that will say
out loud when it's waiting for my input.
And so it will say, "Claude is waiting
for input." And so if I've got the
speaker turned up or I've got my
headphones in, then it will let me know
that it's it's ready because it's it's
dead time. If it's prompted something
and I haven't noticed and it was an hour
ago, then it's a whole wasted time.
Whereas uh if I have it tell me it's
it's waiting. Come on, Alan. What?
Answer this question. Uh tell me what I
should do right and tell me what I
should do next. So yeah, I I use lots of
words um to try and coers it in the
right direction. I'm glad you
[clears throat] mentioned headphones
there cuz I can just imagine the family
going, "Oh, dad, I'm trying to watch a
film." Do
>> you know what's even worse is it's my
voice that it does it. [laughter]
>> I use um I used to talk Piper on Linux.
Uh and many years ago I donated my voice
to an open source project and because my
name is Alan, my voice model appears
near the top in hugging face and so
people download and use my voice for
stuff and I use it as well. It's quite
funny having my own voice coming out of
the computer saying Claude is waiting
for prompt.
>> So for people who have used that in the
past, uh this could be a quite a quite a
strange episode for them who are
listening to you directly as well,
right? They're thinking they're their
kind.
>> Yeah. [laughter]
Awesome. Um so yeah, great. And and
Claude is your go-to tool these days.
>> So yeah, I think I think I'd say Claude
is the primary one I jump to. Uh,
[clears throat]
and I tend to use Gemini, uh, if I've
run out of tokens include. Uh, so if
I've, you know, I don't really want to
keep throwing money at a project. Um,
and so if if it's not useful for me, um,
and you've got to be tight on the
budget. So sometimes I'll just switch to
Gemini because I have a Gemini account,
right? And it's very similar, but Gemini
is seems to be a little bit more
constrained on how you can prompt it.
And so I don't feel as free with the
Gemini even though it has a much higher
context window, larger context window. I
feel I don't feel as free because I feel
like it sometimes says no, I'm not going
to do that. Um and certainly I see that
in typing mind. The prompts that you
give to Claude will work with the same
prompt you give it to Gemini and it
won't. Um the one other uh command line
one that I've used recently is AMP which
has an interesting model um where they
have a free ad supported tier. Um, and I
gave that a test this week and uh
actually asked it to create a web-based
RSS reader. Um, and it did and I was
quite surprised how good it was and I
didn't give it any tools. There were no
MCPS connected to it. I [snorts] just
used pure AMP on its own and it was very
much like claude but it
>> Yeah, it amp is the AMP is the agent
coding agent for from source graph
>> I believe. I think I think I'm making a
huge assumption that we should we should
check that afterwards. [laughter] Um
yeah, I'm pretty sure I'm pretty sure
AMP is from SourceCraft, creators of
Kodi as well, which is uh which is nice.
>> Um so should we jump over to MCP
servers?
>> Yeah, sure.
>> So MCP servers, there are registries
after registries. In fact, there are
registries of registries, I think, in in
uh that that allow you to track all the
different MCP servers. Actually, we had
uh we had uh a great uh session um
around MCP.Run, which is a
[clears throat] a super interesting uh
nice SAS version uh where that can host
MCP servers and things like that as
well. Um but when we when I I remember
when I said to you kind of, you know,
what what are the what are your favorite
MCP servers? What are the MCP servers
that people mostly use? Tell tell us
tell us how you how you discovered what
MCP servers people were mostly using.
>> Ah, that's a great point actually. Hi.
So, we're going to jump into the second
half of our conversation. But first, a
quick shout out to AI Native DevCon. 2
days of hands-on sessions, deep dives,
and honest conversations about what it
means to build AI Native Software
November 18th and 19th in New York, or
join virtually from anywhere. Tickets
and details at a native.io/devcon.
See you there. I have my own, but it
turns out other people have preferences
and I I I could go and ask everyone on
the internet or put a poll on social
media and say, "Hey, what are your
favorite MCPs?" But no, that's that's
far too easy. Um, I wrote a script or I
asked Claude to help me write a script
which basically scraped GitHub looking
for the configuration files that people
list the MCPS in. So, um, MCP.json JSON
is a common one that a lot of them use
and it's a JSON file that lists um in a
structured way all the um the MCPs and
uh so you know you can see in that first
slide we showed a list of some of the
MCPS I'm used I mentioned a couple of
them but I wonder what other people use
and I got it to write a report um
and this is that report. Now bear in
mind this is scraping GitHub. Now, not
everyone is going to um add their
mcb.json to their projects and some
people have private projects and some
people use things other than GitHub like
GitLab or other code hosting tools and
some people will have it totally
in-house. So, this isn't an exhaustive
list of every MCP that everyone's using.
Right? So,
in these reports, uh we found a whole
load of uh configuration files. Uh it
gave me some repositories uh that have
configuration files in them. Um
variables and here we go. There's a a
list of some of the tools that people
have in their configuration files. Now
the thing that I found surprising about
this um [clears throat] was that the
same few tools pop up at the top of the
list quite a lot. And I think this is
part of what I was talking earlier is
people learn from others and they copy
and paste and it's almost like a cargo
cult of copying and pasting stuff from
one place to another. The other thing is
there are repositories which are
collections of other people's settings
files so that people can learn. So it is
a bit wild west and there's a bit of
duplication there. But you can see here
there are some [snorts] of the ones that
I've already mentioned like file system,
being able to access a file system and
sequential thinking and memory. Um, and
yeah, there's there's a bunch of uh
interesting ones like Brave search. So
being able to use Google to search the
web is one option, but there are other
MCPS to be able to search the web with
KI or Brave or um I think there's
probably a Bing one as well. I haven't
looked, but these these are some of the
ones that people are clearly using
because they're showing up in their
settings file. [snorts] And I'd be
interested to like dig deeper into which
ones people are actually using and which
ones are in repos that maybe we can't
see. And I I think there is an
opportunity there to surface this
information about MCPs that people are
using because there it is a bit uh
unknown and a bit daunting for someone
new to know which ones to pick. Um yeah,
>> that's I found that
>> that that's really interesting not just
to see not just to see which ones exist
in configuration but to see which ones
are actively being used in sessions to
see if there's that data. There'll be
interesting actually I wonder if MCP run
share any of that data about usage and
things like that that would be super
beneficial. Um yeah and and I think it's
I I really that really resonates with me
the the the fact that it's people are
trying to learn the best practices for
themselves probably way too much in
isolation and there's a real lack of the
ability to share that I guess in a way
that makes it easily discoverable. Um, I
suspect a lot of people are probably
trying to roll their own here. Uh,
particularly within organizations and
it's much harder obviously to add those
policies outside of an organization to
say to people, hey, here's some great
cursor rules or or or any kind of
configuration for for an agent or or
something like that.
>> Yeah. And you also have to be really
careful because sometimes people are
putting
>> [clears throat]
>> um secrets in their MCP configuration.
And so they actively don't want to share
that not because they don't want people
to know which MCP tools they're using,
but they don't want to accidentally
share their GitHub uh personal access
token or you know some other more
important uh API token. And so there is
this feeling that um I shouldn't share
this, but I feel like there is a space
where we could have [clears throat]
um a database of MCPs that are rated
both by popularity, but also rated by
the quality of them and whether they get
software updates and whether they're
still maintained. um because it's you
know sometimes you configure an MCP in
your uh agent and then it goes away
because they've moved the repository or
they're bought by somebody else or
they've just given up. Um and so it can
be a bit dangerous having this tool
hanging around in your MCP.json file
that you think well this is giving me
value. Is it is it still giving you
value? it could be that that that's
actually a liability and no longer um a
benefit to your project and so there
there does need to be some auditing of
these tools and I know there are some
organizations already doing this uh to
make sure that people aren't getting
themselves uh in trouble using tools
that are no longer maintained in secure
and so on.
>> Yeah. Should we jump into some demo?
Should we uh should we see what these
MCP servers are all about?
>> Okay, let's do a demo using uh Claude.
So if I open Claude, it will see that
there are some uh MCP servers configured
in the uh MCP.json.
And if I then do /m MCP, we should be
able to see the status that all of them
are connected and working successfully.
We probably won't need to use all of
them for this little good demo. All
we're going to do is say uh we've got a
YouTube video over here, one that you
may have seen before. Um, and I want to
create a YouTube description, maybe some
social posts, and a blog post. Uh, let's
see if it'll do all of those. Um,
[clears throat]
grab the transcript of the attached
YouTube video
and create a description,
some social posts,
and an indepth blog post.
have the cups covered.
Let's see how this does.
So, one of the things that Claude loves
doing is creating these plans, right?
These a set of to-dos, plans out what it
wants to do, and then uh and then goes
through them.
>> Yeah. I find ah now you'll see there
it's immediately said it's going to use
a tool. So, it's figured out that YTT is
the one it wants to use, and I'm happy
for it to use YT. Um, so yeah, it
creates the plan and then works through
it. Incidentally, I mentioned AMP
earlier as a another agent. It does a
very similar thing, but the UI is
different and I really like it. It has a
a box on the right hand side and it
keeps the to-do list on screen, whereas
I often find with Claude, it all scrolls
off and I'm not entirely sure what it's
up to at any time. I'm sure I could
bring it back or just scroll back. But
yeah, I was I was quite pleased to see
that AMP keeps it um right there on
screen so I can see it at all times and
see what progress it's making. That's uh
that's the interesting thing with uh
with with something like this. It it it
provides the output directly into the
into the into the terminal, right? But
it doesn't necessarily doesn't
necessarily unless you explicitly ask it
to uh save anything to disk or or it
knows it needs to perhaps for a coding
file or if it wants to make a change to
a coding file or something like that.
>> Yeah. And that's that's a one reason why
I really quite like using uh typing mind
because uh what typing mind will do is
while you're in the web page having a
session uh anything that it creates
there's a copy button just right there
on the screen just like with chat GPT
and all the other web-based ones. But
one of the nice things is you can copy
it with formatting and paste it straight
into a Google doc and it will come out
formatted well for for uh editing
[clears throat] in a Google doc which is
pretty awesome. Right. So it think it's
uh created some files. So now
>> is waiting for human response.
>> I got interrupted by myself there. Um
which is yeah not uncommon. Um so let's
look at the video description.
Uh it's got the name of the person. Does
this match the conversation that you had
in that? Uh then the social posts are a
bit tricky because social posts with all
of these AI tools often like smack at
being written by AI tools and so they
you really need a bit of uh human
interaction to do a bit of uh finessing
of these but it's it gives you some
ideas. It's good for ideiation and
summarizing what's going on. And then
the blog post um let's have a look at
that. [snorts] It's comprehensive if
[clears throat] if nothing else. There's
a lot there. So, um,
>> it's a good starting point, right? Even
even if there's nothing else that uh to
to give
>> to to avoid that writer's block to have
a whole bunch of thought areas.
>> And and to be fair, I did yolo it and
say, "Write the blog post." What I
should have done is say, "Give me some
topics, some, you know, things, and then
we could have worked on it together,
iterated. But for a quick demo, I think
it illustrates that like I I didn't have
to manually go and get the transcript
for that video." [clears throat] And I
realize that's a very simple example,
but there's so many of these that when
you hook them all together and you have
a whole bunch of uh tools working
together, orchestrated by your agent, it
it dramatically accelerates what you can
do because you're not stuck having to go
and manually do things along the way.
And that's that's the thing that I find
is like the the thing that accelerates
everything for me. I actually wrote um a
an MCP server uh which is the one at the
bottom of the list, Gripe. Uh so when I
worked at Ankor, Gripe is a uh
vulnerability uh scanning tool and um I
wanted to have an MCP uh uh server that
would scan the code in the repository
that I'm sat in and make sure it didn't
have any vulnerabilities. Now, I haven't
tested this recently, so I don't know if
this is going to work well. We'll give
it a try and see. Right. So, for this
demo, I'll create a little piece of
software and then I'll see if I can get
it to do a vulnerability scan. And
again, I'll use Claude.
Um, and this is a fresh folder. So, it's
asking me again if I want all those
MCPS. Um now what I'll do is I'll try
and trigger it
>> [snorts]
>> um by making it build something that
will be using outofdate uh software and
by forcing it to use out ofdate software
maybe we'll find some vulnerabilities
assuming my MCP works. So um create a
hello world
Django app
uh app using what's the oldest version
of Django that we think it'll uh be able
to do
[clears throat]
using Django 4.0. There we go. I think
that's old. That sounds old. Uh using
Django 4.0 zero and use UV for
dependencies.
So, all this is going to do is create a
little bit of code. It probably won't do
an awful lot. Um, it'll create uh a
virtual environment using UV [snorts]
and then install whatever Python
packages are required to get this
project bootstrapped.
Um and then
>> for those for those who don't know what
UV is,
>> so a lot of people use uh Python virtual
environments so they can have isolated
uh directories for each of their
projects and uh most of the time people
use Python
VMs and there are other ways to do this
but UV is a relatively new tool written
in Rust and it's a lot faster than using
Python. virtual environments. Um, so
instead of doing uh Python pip install
something, you do UV pip install
something. And actually it's quite
common to see MCP servers that are
delivered using uvx. And so um it's the
equivalent of uh node packages that use
npx use uvx. And in fact that's how uh
the gripe mcp server is delivered. It's
written in Python [snorts] and um all
you put in your MCP uh [clears throat]
JSON is uvx gripe mcp and it will go and
find it. Um and it's um it's
[clears throat] just a really nice way
to contain all of the dependencies for
your Python project in one directory.
>> Nice. So it's uh it's initialized it and
now it's creating the project structure,
the Django project structure.
>> So it's created a little project. Let's
see if we can use the GRE MCP to scan
for vulnerabilities. So, uh, scan the
project for, um,
now what might be interesting here is I
don't actually have Gripe installed, I
don't think. Um, I might, uh, but one of
the things my MCP does is it goes to
find the binary to see if you've got it.
>> Um, and if it can find Gripe in the
path, then it will use it. If it can't
find it, it will go and get the binary.
Um, [snorts] and if Gripe is outdated,
it will try and update it. Um, once it's
found the binary and it's able to run
it, it then has to download a
vulnerability database. Every time you
run GRE for the first time, it pulls
down a vulnerability database, which is
like 100meg or something like that. Um,
so I suspect it's probably doing that
right now. Once it's downloaded the
vulnerability database, it will then
scan the directory. So now it wants to
scan this directory and I say, "Yep,
scan the directory." And what it should
do is potentially find um maybe some
vulnerabilities in whatever dependencies
have been added to this Python project.
And what I would envisionage doing is
rather than doing this manually, I would
probably put it in my agents.m MD or
claude MD to say scan for
vulnerabilities before committing any
code or scan for vulnerabilities before
uploading any code to GitHub because I
don't really want to publish it then
scan um or you know just test that it
works and then scan. I want to make
vulnerability detection something that's
just part of the process. And by having
a vulnerability scanner, whether it's
Gripe or any other uh as an MCP server,
it means it's right there as part of my
developer workflow. It's not an
afterthought. It's not something I do
later. It's something that I can um
integrate right into the process. And of
course, and of course there's more you
could put into there as well, not just
the process, which is super important,
but also the policies to say like, you
know, in the two high, you know,
vulnerabilities that have come back
here, we don't want any high or critical
vulnerabilities. Medium and low is okay
maybe for for a specific policy. And you
can almost like ask it to not check in
anything that has high security
vulnerabilities unless the user
absolutely says so and so forth.
>> Yeah. and and this hasn't given um me a
super detailed explanation of what the
problem is. I can certainly go and
Google that. But if I wanted to ask for
more detail, it now has the the names of
the vulnerabilities. And so it could
describe them to me and give me the
detail and say, "Here's what you should
change." And that actually can be fed to
Claude, my agent, or whichever agent I'm
using. And the agent can then fix that.
So it says, "I recommend you do this
thing here." And I say, "Okay, do it."
And away it goes. and fixes my code. So,
I've found the vulnerability and
potentially I can have Claude just fix
it for me cuz I made a silly mistake and
I said, "Use Django 4.0 and what I
actually meant was Django 4.2."
>> Awesome. So, what's what's next then? Uh
with with I think lots of people now
using MCPs, um what would you say is
kind of uh one of one of the next big
things that we should be we should be
thinking about? So, I mean, it's
predictable, but I'm going to have to
say it's spec driven. It's the the the
process of creating new software. Like,
for someone like me where I can
articulate in English what I want, but I
don't necessarily know the details of
how every single one of the dependencies
get built and how they hook together and
which APIs I should use. And I feel like
if I'm doing that myself and trying to
articulate to the agent how to do those
things, then I'm kind of wasting time.
Someone else must have done this
already. Someone else must have built
this library or used this API. And so I
feel like there should be these reusable
chunks just like the um the settings and
the mcb.json that I found scattered all
over GitHub. I feel like there is a real
opportunity for those little snippets of
um instructions, those specs that we can
scatter throughout our project and have
that do the work that I would normally
have to describe to it or it would have
to go and search and figure it out and
maybe get wrong. And so I want I want to
have something where there is um this
repository and that's you know the Tesla
MCP and the spec registry is is
basically that and that's that's what
drew me towards using Tessle is having
this repository of knowledge that the
agent can call upon to build software in
a way that is um secure, efficient,
reliable and reproducible.
>> Yeah, absolutely. And I think the fact
that the the the sharing capability here
uh within the within the spec registry I
think is I think is very significant
because it really starts providing that
collaborative approach to to development
specifications. Agents are only going to
work as well as the specification as
well as the guidance is. It's very hard
to actually get that guidance that those
policies that that style um correct and
yes sometimes it's absolutely personal
and you might choose to override those
certain settings but for a lot of the
time when you start getting teams you
don't want everyone to to develop in
different ways you want to agree on a
way agree on a stack agree on a uh a
policy that everyone should should abide
by and this is where I think this having
a having a platform having that that
space in which people can contribute,
people can pull down and naturally have
their agents guided uh by these you know
policies, workflows, etc. I think it's
absolutely core to to to that
collaborative development.
>> Yeah. And also it saves a lot of
duplication of effort. Like if I uh have
I'm cranking out a bunch of little
projects, I don't want to have to tell
it every time for Python always use UV
or always do this. I would way rather
have these reusable chunks that I can
just pull down and say right here's my
stack and it goes and gets the spec for
those stack and if those libraries or
frameworks have been updated then so
should the spec be updated and the spec
can be pulled down and if there's a one
missing you know I'm a big advocate for
sharing and so if there's one missing I
should be able to contribute that in a
really straightforward way um so
[snorts] I can give back because you
know I'm a a a uh a proponent of the
open source generation and these little
snippets of markdown. It's [snorts] it's
something that's giving back to those
people who are already creating uh these
these little snippets themselves. And I
I feel like we could all just uh do a
tiny bit and build this corpus of best
practices for uh steering agents
because, you know, we we don't want
everyone to have to yolo their way
through and try and corral and course
correct constantly with their agent. You
really want to be able to say, "This is
what I want. I want to use these
frameworks. I want to use these tools.
Do it." and not have to keep h well I
did ask for that earlier and you didn't
do it and I've already told you do this
and you didn't do it and so I feel like
these specs can keep it on track keep it
on Rails and keep the development
consistent with the last time you ran it
and not a surprise that it's all gone
differently and all gone wrong um I I
prefer that consistent approach than um
than just having an argument with an
agent. It feels like a bad use of my
day. [laughter]
Teslao uh if you wanted to if folks
wanted to to to take a look at the spec
registry and and and how that can be
achieved. So please do please do check
that out. Alan, we're we're at time
already. Um I really appreciate all the
wonderful demos. Um, I think it would be
great for people who are who are kind of
just getting started into MCP, just
getting started into agents to kind of
see what's available, uh, learn what
others are using and how easy actually
it is to really get get started and get
enabled with MCPs, uh, and how it really
truly does extend um, extend the the the
the capabilities of a of an agent. So,
thank you very much for showing that.
>> Thanks very much. I look forward to uh
more of these MCPs appearing and people
sharing what they're doing.
>> Yeah. And I hope the biggest takeaway
isn't that we should all have this nice
little audio announcement saying that
that that Claude is waiting for human
interaction. That's that that shouldn't
be something which everyone should do in
an office. I can only imagine in an open
plan office how frustrating that would
get. [laughter]
>> I'll make sure it happens. Don't worry.
>> Awesome. Alan, thanks again. Appreciate
everyone for uh for joining in. Love to
hear what MCP servers you're using uh
and if there's anything you want to
share and and you know make sure others
can can learn from your knowledge and
your experience and uh and let us know
what you're using. Um thanks again Alan
and thanks all for listening and tune in
next time.